XIAOFENG TANG

Wolli Creek, NSW 2205 ● 0415480728 ● timmy000728@gmail.com

Websites, Portfolios

- www.linkedin.com/in/xiaofeng-tang-77b550227
- https://github.com/maplesoup1

About

I am Fresh graduates from USYD in Master of computer science degree, with strong mathematic background, specialize in full-stack web development. My experience and technical skills will help in working through solutions collaboratively and finishing projects with preformat, decoupled, testable, and maintainable code.

- Self-motivated, creative, and ambitious full-stack JavaScript developer .
- Understanding of IT Project Management Processes and Details.
- Understanding of the SOLID principles.
- Basic understanding of all kinds of project architectures or programming languages that I am not proficient in.
- Interested in different technologies to improve user and coding experience.

Skills

Front End:React, Next.js, HTML5, React Native, Vanilla JavaScript, TypeScript, CSS3, Tailwind CSS, Responsive Design, D3.js, Code Splitting(componentization), Framer Motion, CI/CD pipelines.

Back End: Node.js, Express.js, Flack, GraphQL, RESTful APIs, JWT,

DevOps: GitHub Action.

UI/UX: Color Theory & Typography, Interaction Design Theory, Figma, Photoshop, Canva, Basic 3D modeling and 3D animation rendering by blender.

Database & Cloud: MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Firebase, AWS(EC2, IAM), Google Cloud, Alibaba Cloud(ECS, OSS)

Methodologies: Agile, Waterfall, MVC.

Programing Language: JavaScript, Python, Java.

Understood but not proficient skills: Android Mobile development; Flutter Framework Development; Fundamentals of network security such as TCP/IP protocols, DNS, HTTP/HTTPS, and the operation of Linux and Windows systems in cybersecurity; Basic knowledge of large language modeling and machine learning; Data visualization and analysis.

Education

Master of Science: Computer Science, Expected in 12/2024

USYD

Bachelor of Science: Mathematics, 12/2022

UNSW

Working Experience

Marketing Assistant, 11/2021 to 06/2022

Hungry Panda – Sydney, NSW

- Finding and recruiting selectors through the use of company databases, public social media.
- Actively participate in proposing reasonable changes to the UI of Hungry Panda's mobile apps to improve the user interaction experience.
- Participate in the design process of posters for company events.
- Represented Hungry panda at several large-scale events, such as the Children's Education Fair,
 Sydney Chinatown Night Market, Burwood Carnival, Sydney Housing Show, etc. Meanwhile
 participated in the University of New South Wales (UNSW) and University of Sydney (USYD)
 Orientation as a Hungry Panda Sponsor, actively participating in the venue setup, and
 communicating with student representatives to help new students familiarize themselves with the
 campus.

IT Auditing Assistant, 09/2023 to Current

Derbo Trading - Sydney, NSW

- Assisted design and modify the outsourced company website.
- Assisted in office administration and client communication to help manage auditors' workload.
- Participate in the production of the company's weekly and monthly financial statements, providing
 management with key financial insights through data analysis and interpretation, optimize payroll
 structure.

• Assist in the management of customer and vendor financial accounts, including accounts receivable and accounts payable.

IT Project Assistant Intern, 06/2024 to 07/2024

Guangzhou Smart City Investment Ltd. - Guangzhou, China

- Responsible for maintaining and upgrading the company's official corporate website, as well as the company's internal office automation system.
- Assist in the collection and collation of enterprise data and participate in consulting ERP system integration facing government.

Project experience

Cartoonopia website

Description: Full stack online almanac of characters and cartoons

Technology stack: React, Node.js, Axios, MongoDB.

Personal achievement:

- Front-end style development and back-end database integration for login and registration interface.
- Design and implement a Role-Based Access Control system.
- Implemented a detailed change history log that tracks all edits and additions, displaying the nature of changes and the users involved.
- User Profile page design.

Gooday website

Description: Productivity app, using AI personal assistants to proactively organise life admin bookings between businesses, consumers and networks.

Technology stack: Next.js tailwindcss

Personal achievement:

- Figma prototype UI design.
- Implementation of responsive dynamic effects in the main page.
- GPT Api integration in chat assistant function,

Meeting-Schedule

Description: A full-stack web application that facilitates booking meetings at various platforms, times and locations.

Font-end: Next.js, tailwind css

Backend: kinde authentication, Firebase

Hiking Dating Apps

Description: Android mobile dating app designed specifically for hiking activities.

Technical highlights: Android mobile application development, map and GPS integration, user matching algorithm and

real-time communication function

Career Objectives

Computer Science students graduating from the University of Sydney.Looking for full-stack development working, eager to develop front-end and back-end applications by using my knowledge technologies.